Personal Details	
Name	Nathan Bliss
Email Address	nathanbliss@hotmail.com
Nationality	British
Company Website	http://software-automation.com

#### Summary

BSc in Computer Science

MSc in Telecommunications

3 AWS associate certifications (2017)

AWS Solutions Architect Professional certification (2017)

CompTIA Security+ certification (2017)

Fluent in German: Able to participate in complex technical conversations fluently in the German language (C1/C2 level)
Software Configuration Management / DevOps: Git, BASH, Ansible, Linux SysAdmin (RedHat & Debian), Jenkins, Docker,

Artifactory, Sonatype Nexus, AWS, Google Cloud, Git, GitLab, BitBucket

Atlassian (Bamboo, Jira, Confluence, Crowd)

Extensive LTE /4G Radio / Physical Layer / L1 knowledge and experience

WCDMA (3G), HSPA & LTE 3GPP specification experience

Customer-facing technical support of HSPA (3G Cellular) & LTE (4G Cellular)

Python, GoLang & JavaScript development experience

Web Server Development experience (Django, GoLang, Javascript, HTML5)

Semiconductor company experience: QUALCOMM Snapdragon S4 Wireless Microprocessor, Intel XMM Microprocessors

Website: www.software-automation.com

## Work Experience

## DevOps Engineer [Contractor working via limited company on freelance projects, based in UK] Software Automation Solutions Ltd, UK

October 2019 - November 2019: Advanced Kubernetes training course, including Istio Service Mesh & Kubernetes Security

August 2019 - October 2019: Short-term freelance project work for clients around London via own Ltd Company:

- Improving & refactoring Ansible Playbooks
- AWS/Python Boto scripts & Linux Admin
- AZURE DevOps design, implementation & deployment including use of Terraform *azurerm\_template\_deployment* and use of AZURE Advanced Resource Templates (ARMs) to create & maintain AZURE cloud resources
- Use of different storage classes in AZURE: LRS (Locally Redundant Storage), GRS (Geo-Redundant Storage) & ZRS (Zone Redundant Storage)

June 2019 - August 2019:

- 2 months development effort completing my GoLang/HTML5/JavaScript DevOps tool "DevOps Orchestration Platform": <a href="https://software-automation.com/?page\_id=132#about">https://software-automation.com/?page\_id=132#about</a>

## DevOps Contractor working on CapGemini/HMRC government project

September 2018 - June 2019 (Included 2 contract extensions)

- Ansible automation, deploying proofs of concept of master/agent monitoring technology on RedHat Linux, Prometheus / node-exporter / Grafana, ElasticStack (Kibana / ElasticSearch / Logstash / Filebeat) & Sensu Monitoring System
- Installation & Configuration of AppDynamics Application Performance Monitoring (APM), Machine Agent, Database Agent, Java Agent using Ansible
- Installation & Configuration of Naver PinPoint Java Application Performance Monitoring (APM)
- Terraform & Ansible to launch and configure RedHat-based AWS EC2 instances
- Troubleshooting IBM WebSphere components using SmartBear SoapUI
- Assisting CapGemini Release Manager with GitLab diff comparisons of branches and testing of Ansible playbook runs in order to provide reliable input into code integration decisions

June 2018 - September 2018:

3 months development effort on my GoLang DevOps tool "DevOps Orchestration Platform"

DevOps deployment project for **Ariva.de (Financial Services)**, based working from home via new UK Ltd company March 2018 to June 2018:

- Rollout of Atlassian Bamboo Continuous Integration System
- Configuration of OpenLDAP & resolution of LDAP issues
- Configuration of Java & Maven and resolution of issues
- Successful deployment of Kubernetes prototype on VMWare virtual machine cluster
- Installation & configuration of Sonatype Nexus binary repository & docker registry manager
- Technical admin of TLS CSRs, certificates & keys using Java Keytool

# Publication of my DevOps Article in Admin Magazine

Between March 2018 & May 2018

Publication of a Linux Admin magazine article for one of the top Linux magazines between March and June 2018.

This was also published in print-form across the UK and was available to buy in WHSmith stores across the UK in May 2018.

It was available to buy in print-form in magazine stores across the United States of America in June/July 2018.

Link to online version of article:

http://www.admin-magazine.com/Archive/2018/44/Automated-orchestration-of-a-horizontally-scalable-build-pipeline2

## Freelance DevOps Contractor, Germany

Self-Employed, working via Hays, Aservo & Montash

December 2017 - May 2018

Germany

DevOps & Software Configuration Management for Munich IoT Startup via Hays:

- Installation/Config of Docker-based Concourse CI on Google Cloud Platform & fixing Concourse CI issues
- Kubernetes & MongoDB Configuration
- Scripted Git / BitBucket admin
- Letsencrypt/Certbot certificate admin & config of nginx reverse proxy for SSL termination
- Monitoring script written in Bash to gather stats from Google Cloud Platform VMs
- Resolution of SSH routing issues
- Jira / Atlassian / Confluence REST API scripting

Short DevOps project for **Miele** via Aservo:

- Jenkins config & troubleshooting
- Installation of Atlassian Crowd SSO Platform for Miele and configuration for Active Directory authentication
- Generation of SSL certificates & config of nginx as reverse proxy with HTTPS secure endpoint
- Installation, configuration & REST API scripting of Sonatype Nexus on SuSe Linux
- Working ElasticStack proof-of-concept
- SSL/TLS admin

[From March 2018, starting as freelancer for Ariva.de in Kiel, Germany (via Montash); first month on-site, then finished the 3 month contract working from home in England via new UK limited company].

## LTE Software Integration Consultant (contract)

**Intel Corporation**, January 2017 – December 2017, Duisburg, Germany

- 4G / LTE modem support/logging/troubleshooting, Rel.13 3GPP specs
- Automation of host-based LTE/4G modem tests with Python & BASH
- Automation of MatLab host-based tests using Python & XML
- DevOps / Software Configuration Management tasks with Git, Jenkins & Gerrit

#### **DevOps/Integration Engineer** (contract)

Bosch-SoftTec GmbH, July 2016 - January 2017, Hildesheim, Germany

- Software Configuration Management & Automation using Git
- Enhancement of Jenkins continuous integration pipeline using Groovy scripts, Jenkins plugins & delivery of Artifacts
- Use of Ansible to deploy development environments & Jenkins configurations on CentOS & Ubuntu servers
- Use of Docker to 'containerize' Android development environments for Android App development team
- BASH / Python scripting & fixing issues in existing scripts
- Linux SysAdmin: Troubleshooting & fixing NFS file mount issues; troubleshooting & fixing LDAP issues
- Communicated with team members fluently in German
- Solved major logging issue using a Python script that allowed partitioning & extraction of compressed HTML payload data from logs

#### **DevOps Engineer** (contract)

Intel Corporation, March 2016 - June 2016, Munich, Germany

- Git / Jenkins / Gerrit software configuration management & build management of Android / LTE Modem builds
- Development & improvements to Python Django web server
- Developed a build automation script for local host based Android & Modem build compilation

## **Software Configuration Management Consultant** (contract)

**NXP Semiconductors**, September 2014 – November 2015, Hamburg, Germany

- Software Configuration Management / DevOps for semiconductor hardware design data
- Designed & implemented multi-threaded Linux Bash & PERL scripts for automation of software config tasks
- Designed and implemented automation system to collect stats & reclaim disk storage space, saving high storage costs
- Developed multi-threaded GUI apps in Perl Tk & TCL Tk to speed up & automate Linux-based DevOps/configuration management processes. One Python script reduced an error-prone 4-6 hour task to a 100% accurate 30 second one
- Technical Support given to users for DevOps / software configuration management tasks
- Implemented SOAP protocol & associated SOAP XML templates for Collabnet/Subversion administration

## Software Engineer (contract)

SONY, February 2014 – August 2014, Lund, Sweden

- Developed an Android / SIP / IMS Test Harness & extendible Framework with Wireshark, Java, ADB, Android port forwarding, Python & LUA scripts, with the Linux Netcat utility target-compiled for Android with the Android NDK
- Contributed to testing and bug-fixing of SIP / IMS Java code, , with reference to RCS 5.1/5.2/JOYN specs
- Wrote test strategy for Sony's Rich Communication Services (RCS) product, with reference to RCS 5.1/5.2/JOYN specs
- Contributed proof of concept Java code for IMAP-4 messaging project

#### **Software Engineer** (contract)

Encompass Digital Media, August 2013 – November 2013, London

- Developed a C#.NET WPF application, interfacing into an MS SQL Server relational database
- Developed optimized stored procedures on Microsoft SQL Server platform
- Developed Python & Perl scripts to carry out digital media asset management, prototype REST API framework in ASP.NET, Google Apps Script code to automate REST API based tasks

### LTE Technical Support Consultant (contract)

QUALCOMM, April 2012 – April 2013, Farnborough, Hampshire

- Used Qualcomm QXDM/APEX/QCAT logging tools to find and resolve bugs and issues for Snapdragon S4 customers
- Successfully resolved baseband LTE L1, AS & NAS issues for Snapdragon S4 customers
- Appointed main Europe point-of-contact for LTE & WCDMA Inter-RAT issues
- Used 3GPP specs to resolve complex issues for customers: LTE Physical Layer, MAC, RLC, RRC, NAS, SIP & IMS layers (3GPP 36.101, 36.211, 36.212, 36.213, 25.101, 25.211, 25.212, 25.213, 25.214, 36.331, 25.331, 36.321, 36.322, 24.008, 36.306, 25.306, 24.301, 36.304, 25.304)
- IOT trips to customer labs for resolution of LTE & Inter-RAT issues for MDM9615 & MSM8960 Snapdragon S4 processors Developed automated log analysis Python scripts & spreadsheets for calculating throughput, verifying cell (re)selections &
- handovers and validating the LTE paging cycle calculations

#### Component Verification Specialist (LTE Laver 1)

Intel Corporation, October 2011 – February 2012, Dresden, Germany

- Utilised an Aeroflex 7100, Rohde & Schwarz SMU200 & San Jole LTE analyser to develop L1 test cases resolve issues using Java/Eclipse framework
- Use of SVN & ClearCase for source control
- Used LTE L1 3GPP specifications 36.101, 36.211, 36.212, 36.213 to debug L1 radio issues
- Successfully carried out first cabling & configuration of an Elektrobit F8 Channel Emulator for MIMO tests: UE microprocessor board <=> Elektrobit F8 channel emulator <=> San Jole Air Interface analyser (passive) <=> Aeroflex 7100 eNodeB (BTS) Simulator.

## LTE Test Consultant (contract)

Anite Telecoms, February 2011 – September 2011

- Developed test cases in C++ using Anite Development Toolset
- Contributed to development of LTE Test Automation System
- Analysed HSPA+ & LTE logs and helped to resolve bugs & issues at L1, L2, L3 & L4
- Wrote LTE test plans for test simulator products
- Wrote scripts & apps in Excel VBA, Python & Perl to automate log analysis & generate graphs

## HSPA+ Test Consultant (contract)

**Picochip**, November 2010 – January 2011

- Success Integration of 64QAM downlink with Aeroflex TM500 down to less than 1% block error rate
- Successfully ported TCL HSDPA/MAC-ehs test scripts & library to be compatible with HSPA+ and 64QAM
- Implemented calculations in TCL library for throughput & block error rates
- Ported TCL library between Aeroflex TM500 platforms

## Senior Software Engineer [Femtocell Project] (contract)

Technicolor (subsidiary of Thomson), March 2010 – August 2010

- Aeroflex TM500 support & Java multi-threaded GUI programming for test automation with Aeroflex TM500
- Contributed Perl module to the team's test automation system
- Developed UMTS R99 & HSPA TTCN3 test cases & TTCN code for RANAP, HNBAP & NAS protocols
- ClearCase version control: Merging of TTCN3 code & scripted automation of report gathering for managers

### Field Application Engineer (LTE & HSPA+ Technical Support)

**Aeroflex,** June 2008 – February 2010 (1 year 9 months)

- Protocol Stack & Physical Layer technical support of Aeroflex TM500 for WCDMA & LTE
- HSPA & LTE log analysis, including analysis of DSP logs
- Rel.7 3GPP specs: 25.211, 25.212, 25.213, Rel.8 3GPP specs: 36.211, 36.212, 36.213, 36.331
- Use of Aeroflex PXI SigGen, R&S CMU200, SMU200, SMJ100A & spectrum analysers to analyse & resolve issues
- Python scripting (including app to automate TM500 firmware upgrade)
- Provided formal LTE training presentations to customers

#### HSPA+ Test Consultant (contract)

Ericsson, 2007 – 2008, HSPA+ Project based in Nuremberg, Germany.

- Contributed to HSPA test cases for HSPA+ project
- Successful installation & configuration of two prototype Ericsson IMS/SIP servers
- Analysed WCDMA logs & SIP/IMS logs & worked with developers to resolve issues
- Designed & developed test analysis system with Excel VBA, Perl & Wireshark, to automate throughput graphing

#### Senior Software Development Engineer

**Anritsu**, 2006 – 2007

- Developed UMTS/HSPA tests on MD8480 RTD system
- Developed MS Access test result database & Perl test automation scripts
- Customer technical support of UMTS RTD system

# Interoperability Test Team Lead

**RIM (BlackBerry),** 2002 – 2006 (4 years)

- IOT of Blackberry devices at operator & vendor labs
- GSM & (E)GPRS log analysis
- Wrote test specs for GSM, GPRS, EDGE & SIM toolkit, WAP & MMS test cases
- Worked with supplier TTPCom to debug radio code
- C programming: Successfully modified Blackberry logging tool analyse signals content
- Python test scripts

## - Promoted to IOT team lead after 3 years with the company

#### **Professional Qualifications**

November 2017: CompTIA Security+ Certification

Jun-Aug 2017: AWS Certified Architect (PROFESSIONAL), AWS Certified Developer, AWS Certified SysOps Administrator Jul 2007, Accredited Symbian C++ Developer

May 2002, Foundation Certificate in Software Testing (BCS/ISEB)

Dec 2001, CCNA

## Academic Qualifications & Experience

## MSc in Telecommunications Technology (Aston University, Birmingham)

Research Project Placement: BT Labs (Project: IPSec and IPv6 security)

# **BSc 2.1 Hons Degree in Computer Science** (Kingston)

Final Year Project: C++ image processing / graphics / motion analysis

### **3<sup>rd</sup> year industrial placement: Philips Research** (C++ graphic development)

- Filed patent in image processing with Philips

## Languages

German: Fluent (C1/C2 standard)